[Xuling Manor] I took her pulse the other day
[Xuling Manor] قمت بقياس نبضها في ذلك اليوم
and found that she was poisoned.
ووجدت أنها تسمم.
She's dying.
إنها تحتضر.
But
ولكن
I've detoxified her.
لقد أزلتها من السموم.
I've never seen you
أنا لم أرك قط
treat a girl this nicely.
تعامل الفتاة بشكل جيد.
Don't forget
لا تنسى
that she is planted in your residence by Zhou Han.
أنها زرعت في مسكنك من قبل تشو هان.
If a woman
إذا كانت امرأة
can cause the fall of Xuling Manor,
يمكن أن يتسبب في سقوط Xuling Manor ،
then I do not deserve
ثم أنا لا أستحق
to be the tycoon here.
ليكون الملياردير هنا.
Well... I have to go now.
حسنًا ... علي أن أذهب الآن.
See you tomorrow.
أراك غدا.
Qianmu, let's depart.
Qianmu ، دعنا نرحل.
[Xuling Manor]
[إكسولينج مانور]
What are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظر؟
Get on the carriage.
اصعد على العربة.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Stay still.
اثبت مكانك.
Young Master, time to go.
السيد الشاب ، حان الوقت للذهاب.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
I was afraid I might disturb you.
كنت خائفة من أن أزعجك.
What are you thinking?
بماذا تفكر؟
I was massaging her feet.
كنت أقوم بتدليك قدميها.
Set out now.
انطلق الآن.
You're the Young Master of Xuling Manor.
أنت السيد الشاب في Xuling Manor.
Why did you lie to me that you're a physician?
لماذا كذبت علي أنك طبيب؟
I did not lie to you.
لم اكذب عليك.
It was you who got the wrong person.
كنت أنت من حصلت على الشخص الخطأ.
Well...
نحن سوف...
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
What was it?
ماذا كان؟
Nothing.
لا شئ.
(She is blushing)
(إنها تحمر خجلاً)
(and faltering.)
(ويتعثر).
(Don't tell me)
(لا تخبرني)
(this stupid woman has really fallen for me.)
(لقد وقعت هذه المرأة الغبية من أجلي حقًا).
It's quite hot in here.
الجو حار جدا هنا.
It is.
إنها.
[The Blessed Bride] [Episode 5]
[العروس المباركة] [الحلقة 5]
Hi, Albert.
مرحبًا ألبرت.
Long time no see.
وقت طويل لا رؤية.
Hey, dude, what's up?
مرحبا يا صاح كيف الاحوال؟
(I should show her how good my English is)
(يجب أن أوضح لها مدى جودة لغتي الإنجليزية)
(to let her know the great disparity between us)
(لإعلامها بالتفاوت الكبير بيننا)
(so that she won't dare to adore me anymore.)
(حتى لا تجرؤ على الإعجاب بي بعد الآن).
Let me introduce my wife.
اسمحوا لي أن أقدم زوجتي.
Hi.
أهلاً.
My husband often talks about you.
كثيرا ما يتحدث زوجي عنك.
(Don't think you're the only one who can speak English.)
(لا تعتقد أنك الشخص الوحيد الذي يمكنه التحدث باللغة الإنجليزية.)
My wife is a very enthusiastic person.
زوجتي شخص متحمس جدا.
I'm flattered.
أنا أشعر بالإطراء.
Since we are all good at English,
نظرًا لأننا جميعًا جيدون في اللغة الإنجليزية ،
why don't we speak the dialect we use in our hometown?
لماذا لا نتحدث باللهجة التي نستخدمها في بلدتنا؟
Sure, mate. (*Northeastern Mandarin)
بالتأكيد يا صديقي.  (* شمال شرق الماندرين)
Mate?
رَفِيق؟
Streuth!
ستروث!
So we come from the same place.
لذا أتينا من نفس المكان.
That sure makes me feel that we're close friends.
هذا بالتأكيد يجعلني أشعر بأننا أصدقاء مقربون.
So you're my fellow townsman.
إذن أنت زملائي في المدينة.
Yeah!
نعم!
Don't be a drain on our business talk.
لا تستنزف حديثنا عن العمل.
You're so handsome. (*speaking Cantonese)
انت وسيم جدا.  (* يتحدث الكانتونية)
We should have some tea together sometime.
يجب أن نتناول بعض الشاي معًا في وقت ما.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
Can you understand our conversation?
هل يمكنك فهم حديثنا؟
There are varieties of dialects
هناك أنواع مختلفة من اللهجات
being spoken in China.
يتحدث بها في الصين.
If you can't even understand what we were saying,
إذا كنت لا تستطيع حتى فهم ما قلناه ،
how can you accuse me of being a drain on your business talk?
كيف تتهمني بأنني استنزاف حديث عملك؟
How ridiculous.
كم هذا سخيف.
I'll take my leave then.
سآخذ إجازتي بعد ذلك.
Bye, handsome.
مع السلامة أيها الوسيم.
Bye.
وداعا.
See you.
أرك لاحقًا.
What's going on, mate?
ما الذي يحدث يا صديقي؟
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
What did my wife tell you?
ماذا قالت لك زوجتي؟
Please tell me everything.
من فضلك قل لي كل شيء.
Ling Qiye, how dare you think
لينغ تشي ، كيف تجرؤ على التفكير
that you know more dialects than me?
أن تعرف لهجات أكثر مني؟
I'm never scared of competing.
أنا لا أخاف من المنافسة.
(It turns out that what he made me drink that day was the antidote.)
(اتضح أن ما جعلني أشربه في ذلك اليوم كان الترياق).
(But why?)
(لكن لماذا؟)
(Since he had already known)
(منذ أن عرف بالفعل)
(that I came after the Ling family.)
(أنني جئت بعد عائلة لينغ).
Did he do it to render good for evil?
وهل فعل ذلك لجلب الخير بالشر؟
Could it be
هل من الممكن ذلك
that he's not the kind of person my brother thinks he is?
أنه ليس من النوع الذي يعتقده أخي؟
But even if he is not,
ولكن حتى لو لم يكن كذلك ،
he is one of the Lings.
هو واحد من Lings.
As long as he has the surname "Ling",
طالما أنه يحمل لقب "لينغ" ،
he can never be a kind person.
لا يمكنه أبدًا أن يكون شخصًا لطيفًا.
No matter how good-looking he is
مهما كان حسن المظهر
or how upright he is,
أو مدى استقامته ،
he can't be trusted.
لا يمكن الوثوق به.
[Adapted from the comic "My Dear Concubine" drawn by Ah Weiwei and Muxi Huanhuan]
[مقتبس من الفيلم الكوميدي "My Dear Concubine" الذي رسمه Ah Weiwei و Muxi Huanhuan]
♪Looking pretty in the wedding gown, I'm forced to get married♪
♪ أبدو جميلة في ثوب الزفاف ، أجبرت على الزواج ♪
♪Within these high walls, can I escape after having met you?♪
♪ داخل هذه الأسوار العالية هل أستطيع الهروب بعد أن التقيت بك؟ ♪
♪Late at night, I can't fall asleep with so much sadness♪
♪ في وقت متأخر من الليل ، لا أستطيع النوم مع الكثير من الحزن
♪Despite the many restrictions, I live a carefree life♪
على الرغم من القيود العديدة ، أعيش حياة خالية من الهموم
♪Turns out my mood will be much better with you around♪
♪ تبين أن مزاجي سيكون أفضل بكثير معك حولك
♪Seeing your smile, I will not run away from here again♪
برؤية ابتسامتك لن أهرب من هنا مرة أخرى
♪Enjoying the sunset in the bamboo forest, your face crosses my mind♪
استمتع بغروب الشمس في غابة الخيزران ، وجهك يخطر ببالي ♪
♪I'm falling for you gradually although I say otherwise♪
♪ أنا أقع في حبك تدريجياً رغم أنني أقول غير ذلك ♪
♪I'd like to say♪
♪ أود أن أقول ♪
♪I want this to be sweet and romantic between us♪
♪ اريد ان يكون هذا حلو ورومانسي بيننا
♪I want to marry you and grow old with you so badly♪
♪ أريد أن أتزوجك وأكبر معك بشدة
♪I want to witness the beauty of this world with you♪
♪ اريد ان اشهد جمال هذا العالم معك
♪Never mind that time passes and our hairs turn gray♪
♪ لا تهتم بمرور الوقت وشعرنا يتحول إلى اللون الرمادي
♪I want this to be sweet and romantic between us♪
♪ اريد ان يكون هذا حلو ورومانسي بيننا
♪I want to marry you and grow old with you so badly♪
♪ أريد أن أتزوجك وأكبر معك بشدة
♪I want to witness the beauty of this world with you♪
♪ اريد ان اشهد جمال هذا العالم معك
♪Never mind that time passes and our hairs turn gray♪
♪ لا تهتم بمرور الوقت وشعرنا يتحول إلى اللون الرمادي
♪Looking pretty in the wedding gown, I'm forced to get married♪
♪ أبدو جميلة في ثوب الزفاف ، أجبرت على الزواج ♪
♪Within these high walls, can I escape after having met you?♪
♪ داخل هذه الأسوار العالية هل أستطيع الهروب بعد أن التقيت بك؟ ♪
♪Late at night, I can't fall asleep with so much sadness♪
♪ في وقت متأخر من الليل ، لا أستطيع النوم مع الكثير من الحزن
♪Despite the many restrictions, I live a carefree life♪
على الرغم من القيود العديدة ، أعيش حياة خالية من الهموم
♪Turns out my mood will be much better with you around♪
♪ تبين أن مزاجي سيكون أفضل بكثير معك حولك
♪Seeing your smile, I will not run away from here again♪
برؤية ابتسامتك لن أهرب من هنا مرة أخرى
♪Enjoying the sunset in the bamboo forest, your face crosses my mind♪
استمتع بغروب الشمس في غابة الخيزران ، وجهك يخطر ببالي ♪
♪I'm falling for you gradually although I say otherwise♪
♪ أنا أقع في حبك تدريجياً رغم أنني أقول غير ذلك ♪
♪I'd like to say♪
♪ أود أن أقول ♪
♪I want this to be sweet and romantic between us♪
♪ اريد ان يكون هذا حلو ورومانسي بيننا
♪I want to marry you and grow old with you so badly♪
♪ أريد أن أتزوجك وأكبر معك بشدة
♪I want to witness the beauty of this world with you♪
♪ اريد ان اشهد جمال هذا العالم معك
♪Never mind that time passes and our hairs turn gray♪
♪ لا تهتم بمرور الوقت وشعرنا يتحول إلى اللون الرمادي
♪I want this to be sweet and romantic between us♪
♪ اريد ان يكون هذا حلو ورومانسي بيننا
♪I want to marry you and grow old with you so badly♪
♪ أريد أن أتزوجك وأكبر معك بشدة
♪I want to witness the beauty of this world with you♪
♪ اريد ان اشهد جمال هذا العالم معك
♪Never mind that time passes and our hairs turn gray♪
♪ لا تهتم بمرور الوقت وشعرنا يتحول إلى اللون الرمادي
[The Blessed Bride]
[العروس المباركة]
[Adapted from "My Dear Concubine" on Cloud Comic]
[مقتبس من "My Dear Concubine" on Cloud Comic]